afuturewithus.com 2014-03-07

# Online Privacy Statement

Al-Futtaim Trading (Private) Limited (Al-Futtaim) is dedicated to protecting your privacy and safeguarding your personally identifiable information. Our aim is to consistently exceed expectations in terms of the products and services we provide to our customers. We strive to create an online experience that is responsive to our customersâ€™ needs by using the information you entrust us with responsibly. Al-Futtaim is committed to respecting your privacy and adhering to the principles of applicable data protection and privacy laws throughout the world.

We have provided this Privacy Statement as an explanation of the information we collect, how we use it, and how the use of this information can benefit your experience on our website and during your relationship with us. We wish to help you make informed decisions, so please take a moment to read the sections below.

  * AL-FUTTAIM
  * TYPES OF INFORMATION WE COLLECT
  * PURPOSE FOR COLLECTION, PROCESSING, AND DISCLOSURE
  * CONSENT
  * DATA TRANSFERS ACROSS INTERNATIONAL BORDERS
  * ACCESS TO PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION
  * SECURITY SAFEGUARDS
  * ON-LINE TECHNOLOGIES
  * LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES
  * MINORS
  * ACCURACY & PRIVACY
  * CONTACT US
  * UPDATES TO THE PRIVACY STATEMENT

## AL-FUTTAIM

In order to provide multiple access points to the services and products we offer, Al-Futtaim operates directly, or through its affiliates or service providers, many websites, including www.futtaim.com, www.futtaim.ae, www.al-futtaim.com and www.al-futtaim.ae. Any of these websites may ask for and collect personally identifiable information in order to enhance your experience and provide you with relevant information.

## TYPES OF INFORMATION WE COLLECT

Al-Futtaim collects information about visitors to our websites so that we can provide an experience that is responsive to our customers needs. Information may be collected as part of: (i) fulfilling information requests, (ii) registering for newsletter or programme membership, (iii) submitting a job application, or (iv) responding to communications from us (e.g., surveys or promotional offers or correspondence). We endeavour to collect information only with your knowledge and with your permission if necessary. The types of personally identifiable information that we collect may include your name, home, work and email addresses, telephone and fax numbers, and other information necessary to fulfill special requests.

Al-Futtaim may also collect non-personally identifiable information about you, such as your use of our websites, communication preferences and responses to promotional offers and surveys.

## PURPOSE FOR COLLECTION, PROCESSING, AND DISCLOSURE

**Collection & Use**

Al-Futtaim is fully committed to providing you with information about the collection and use of personally identifiable information (PII) furnished by, or collected from, visitors while using our websites, products and services. It is our practice not to ask you for information unless we need it or intend to use it. Some of the primary purposes for collecting your PII are as follows:

  1. Providing services such as processing a transaction (e.g. fulfilling a request for information)
  2. Marketing and communicating with you in relation to the products and services offered by Al-Futtaim, our strategic marketing partners, and other trusted third parties
  3. Performing market research via surveys to better serve your needs, improve the effectiveness of our websites, your experience with Al-Futtaim, our various types of communications, advertising campaigns, and / or promotional activities

You will always be offered the choice not to submit your PII or to decide what communications you would like to receive from us. However, doing so may cause certain transactions to be affected.

## Processing and Disclosure

In most cases, the information you provide is added to a local or global database. In the course of processing your information, it may be necessary to transfer your PII to Al-Futtaimâ€™s affiliates and / or third party service providers located in the United Kingdom and throughout the world for the purposes outlined within this Privacy Statement. As a general practice, Al-Futtaim does not sell, rent or give physical possession of your PII to unaffiliated third parties outside the Al-Futtaim system. Situations in which Al-Futtaim may disclose your information to others include:

  1. When we have received your consent to do so 
  2. In situations where sharing or disclosing your information is required in order to offer you products or services you desire (e.g., a job application) 
  3. When companies or services providers that perform business activities on behalf of Al-Futtaim require such information (e.g. customer support services, market research administration or database management services) 
  4. When access to your PII is necessary to facilitate business operations or meet contractual obligations 
  5. To comply with legal or regulatory requirements or obligations in accordance with applicable law or court order 
  6. In case of emergency such as to safeguard the life, health, or property of an individual

If information is shared as mentioned above, we seek to limit the scope of information that is furnished to the amount necessary for the performance of the specific function. Unless otherwise precluded by legal process, we require third parties to protect your PII and abide by applicable privacy laws and regulations.

## CONSENT

As part of our commitment to keep you informed, we may mail, email, telephone or contact you by other means to notify you of new Al-Futtaim products and services or upcoming Al-Futtaim special offers, events, enhancements or other relevant information that may be of interest to you. You may also receive mailings or other communications from carefully selected third parties. We always offer you the option to decline any or all of these communications by following the directions included in our emails or other communications or by contacting Al-Futtaim directly.

We would like to keep all customers informed and equally able to take advantage of the benefits offered by Al-Futtaim and its strategic marketing partners. However, if you reside outside of the United Arab Emirates, certain data privacy regulations may require us to obtain your permission before we send you information that you have not requested from us.

In some cases your permission will be implied from the nature of the service requested or transaction undertaken. For example, Al-Futtaim may collect and use personally identifiable information that you volunteer or behavioural data or information collected in the aggregate. In addition, your permission will be deemed given for communications from us that are necessary to fulfill transactions and services that you request.

In certain circumstances, we will seek your express permission when we collect information that is regarded under certain data privacy regulations to be sensitive in nature (e.g., information revealing racial or ethnic origin or health conditions).

## DATA TRANSFERS ACROSS INTERNATIONAL BORDERS

Al-Futtaim endeavours to provide you a consistent level of customer service. To achieve this goal, we have established a global network comprised of properties, offices, data centres, trusted marketing partners, service providers, customer contact centres and trained colleagues around the world. 

The nature of our business and operations may require us to transfer your information, including personally identifiable information (PII), to other group companies, properties, centres of operations, data centres, or service providers that may be located in countries outside of your own. Although the data protection and other laws of these various countries may not be as comprehensive as those in your own country, Al-Futtaim will take appropriate steps to ensure that your PII is protected and handled as described in this Privacy Statement. 

## ACCESS TO PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION

To ensure that your personally identifiable information (PII) is accurate and up to date, we encourage you to regularly review and update your information as appropriate (e.g. in the event your home or email address changes or you wish to add an additional method for us to communicate with you). If you are registered under our recruitment portal, you can review and update your individual profile online. Please note that in an effort to prevent the unauthorised disclosure of your PII, you may be asked to provide proof of identity (or other authentication materials) together with the completed access request form. Access to PII cannot be provided by telephone.

Occasionally, information that you request to be removed will be retained in certain files for a period of time in order to properly resolve disputes or to troubleshoot problems. In addition, some types of information may be stored indefinitely on "back up" systems or within log files due to technical constraints or financial or legal requirements. Therefore, you should not always expect that all of your PII will be completely removed from our databases in response to your request.

## SECURITY SAFEGUARDS:

Al-Futtaim recognises the importance of information security, and is constantly reviewing and enhancing our technical, physical, and logical security rules and procedures. This websites and its hosting servers have security measures in place to help protect your personally identifiable information against loss, misuse and alteration while under our control. Although "guaranteed security" does not exist either on or off the Internet, we safeguard your information using both procedural and technical safeguards, including password controls, "firewalls" and the use of up to 128-bit encryption based on a Class 3 Digital Certificate issued by VeriSign, Inc. This allows for the use of Secure Sockets Layer (SSL), an encryption method used to help protect your data from interception and hacking while in transit.

## ON-LINE TECHNOLOGIES:

Al-Futtaim may use cookies, invisible pixels and web beacons to obtain information about you while visiting our website. A cookie is a very small text file that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. It assigns the computer with a unique identifier, which in turn, becomes your identification card whenever you return to this website.

Cookies are designed to save you time because they help us to provide you with a customised experience without you having to remind us of your preferences each time you return to our web pages. Al-Futtaim cookies are not designed to damage your files, nor can they read information from other files on your computer hard drive.

Cookies can also help us provide you with a personalised on-line experience in the following ways:

  * They remember your user name and password for future visits so log in is easier and faster
  * They ensure you are provided with the appropriate frames and content
  * They ensure you obtain all requested information
  * They help us deliver communications that are relevant and responsive to your interests and location

Al-Futtaim cookies are limited to this website only and are not designed to follow you when travelling on the Internet after leaving this website. We track the usage of our website in order to better meet your needs and to help make it easier for you to find information in the future. Please note that in addition various third parties may also place cookies on your computer's hard drive. Al-Futtaim is not responsible for the presence or absence of third party cookies or for the technological capabilities or practices employed by third parties in connection with third party cookies.

If you would prefer not to have the benefits of cookies, your Internet browser can be adjusted to treat cookies in different ways. Depending upon the type of browser you are using, you may be able to configure your browser so that: (i) you are prompted to accept or reject cookies on an individual basis or (ii) you may be able to prevent your browser from accepting any cookies at all. You should refer to the supplier or manufacturer of your web browser for specific details about cookie security. However, you should also understand that rejecting cookies might affect your ability to perform certain transactions on this website and our ability to recognise your browser from one visit to the next.

Al-Futtaim also uses invisible pixels, sometimes called web beacons, to count how many people visit certain web pages. Information collected from invisible pixels is used and reported in the aggregate and does not contain personally identifiable information. Al-Futtaim may use this information to improve marketing programs and content.

## LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES:

In order to anticipate your needs, Al-Futtaim provides links to other websites for your convenience and information. Al-Futtaim is not responsible or liable for any content presented by or contained on any independent website, including, but not limited to, any advertising claims or marketing practices. Please note that while Al-Futtaim will protect your information on this website, we cannot control and will not be responsible for the privacy policies of third party websites, including websites owned or controlled by independent franchisees, third party owners, or websites not controlled or authorised by Al-Futtaim.

Third party web sites that are accessed through links on our website have separate privacy and data collection practices and security measures. We have no responsibility or liability for the practices, policies and security measures implemented by third parties on their websites and recommend that you review the privacy statements and policies of linked websites to understand how those websites collect, use and store information.

## MINORS:

Al-Futtaim does not seek to obtain nor does it wish to receive personally identifiable information directly from minors; however, we cannot always determine the age of persons who accesses and uses our website. If a minor (as defined by applicable law) provides us with his/her data without parental or guardian consent, we encourage the parent or guardian to contact us to have this information removed and to unsubscribe the minor from future Al-Futtaim marketing communications.

## ACCURACY & PRIVACY:

While every attempt is made to ensure that the information presented in all items on this web site is both accurate and useful, Al-Futtaim does not make any warranty regarding the content or accuracy of the materials accessible through this website or its host server. In order to protect the identities and privacy of our employees, pseudonyms and stock imagery has been used throughout this website. We accept no responsibility for the accuracy of statements or information presented or liability for any and all actions that may consequently arise.

## CONTACT US:

If you would like to update your information, modify your communication preferences or if you do not want to receive marketing communications from Al-Futtaim in the future, you can contact us by email:

If you have comments or questions regarding Al-Futtaimâ€™s data privacy practices or this Privacy Statement, you may contact us by email:

## UPDATES TO THE PRIVACY STATEMENT:

Al-Futtaim may amend this Privacy Statement from time to time in order to meet changes in the regulatory environment, business needs or to satisfy the needs of our strategic marketing partners, and service providers. Updated versions will be posted to our website and date stamped so that you are always aware of when the Privacy Statement was last updated.

**Issued: November 2008**
